Colleen Kiernan

215 Maple Street Conshohocken, PA 19428 Phone: (973)294-1415 E-mail: ckiernan91@gmail.com

Website: https://www.linkedin.com/in/colleenkiernan
https://www.linkedin.com/in/colleenkiernan
https://colleenkiernan
http://colleenkiernan
http://colleenkiernan
http://colleenkiernan
http://colleenkiernan
http://colleenkiernan
https://www.linkedin.com/in/colleenkiernan
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/colleenkiernan
<a href="https://wwww.linkedin.com/in/colleenkiernan
<a href="https://www.linkedin.com/in/colleenkiern



Objective

Qualified educator with two years of varied instructional professional experience. My goal is to build a long-term career as an elementary teacher with opportunities for career growth, while encouraging creativity and higher-order thinking to increase academic performance.

Certifications

Pennsylvania Instructional 1 Teaching Certificate, Type 61 July 2013

Certified grades Preschool through 4

New Jersey Standard Teaching Certificate, #934051January 2014

Certified grades Preschool through 3

Experience

Classroom Teacher, Grade 2 (September 2014 –Present) Saint Virgil Academy (Morris Plains, New Jersey)

- Successfully developed and currently maintaining a 21st century classroom which engages students of all learning styles by implementing whole group instruction, small group intervention, and one-on-one basic skills reinforcement.
- Design and develop learning experiences to fulfill the academic, social and intellectual needs of diverse groups of students.
- Pilot new academic program Words Their Way Word Study for Phonics, Spelling, and Vocabulary Instruction.
- Effectively create, communicate and collaborate through STEM, inquiry-based learning, differentiation and cross-curriculum lessons aligned with common core standards and ACE collaborative instruction.
- Deliver ongoing performance and summative assessments to allow for smooth transitions of groups in the elementary classroom.

Instructional Classroom Aide, Grade 2 (September 2013 –June 2014) Saint Vincent de Paul School (Stirling, New Jersey)

- Differentiated and modified instruction for small groups.
- Assisted piloting of Words Their Way Word Study.
- Developed alternate curriculum for small groups of struggling students and implemented Whole Brain Teaching.
- Co-taught with lead teacher in a variety of subjects while formally and informally assessing students' academic and behavioral progress

Student Teaching Experience

First Grade (October 2012- March 2013)

Blue Mountain East Elementary (Orwigsburg, Pennsylvania)

- Assisted FUNdations phonics program.
- Team taught a self-contained first-grade classroom.
- Developed and implemented interactive smart board lessons across all subject areas aligned with common core standards.
- Participated in parent-teacher conferences, IST, CST and IEP meetings.

Kindergarten (March 2013- May 2013)

Lincoln Early Childhood Center (Allentown, Pennsylvania)

- Effectively instructed self-contained full day kindergarten.
- Differentiated variety of lessons to accommodate students of all levels including ELLs aligned with the common core standards.
- Attended IST and IEP meetings, teacher in-service days.

Education

Kutztown University (May 2013)

Bachelor of Science in Education

- Major in Elementary Education Preschool to Fourth Grade.
- Graduated Cum Laude. GPA: 3.53/4.00, Major GPA: 3.86/4.00
- Dean's List Fall 2010-Spring 2013

University of Valladolid (June 2011-July 2011)

Valladolid, Spain

- Participated in a Summer Semester Abroad at University of Valladolid
- Worked to improve Spanish fluency

Skills

- Effective and organized classroom management.
- Experience with STEM, STEAM, and STREAM.
- Accomplished in Words Their Way Word Study.
- Highly proficient in use of Smart Board and Promethean Board technology.
- Skilled in use of Kidspiration, Scratch and Microsoft Offices.